and our mothers were married like that
and you were born from relations that
they didn't plan is the boy that saw you
and loved you didn't come and ask you
can I I date you didn't come and and ask
you can can we get engaged you know
didn't come with a ring surprise ring
Safari P will you marry me and it's all
over
Facebook you know that that was never
there the waves are raging Rising high
but I've learned to be at peace and I
pray you find the same piece
today it's tough you've considered a
separation you're considering a divorce
you're now considering even separating
bedrooms some have already separated
bedrooms one of you is sleeping with the
children you confuse the
children if it must get to a point you
don't want to sleep with your spouse
sleep in the kitchen not in the
children's
bedroom and wake up early enough before
they wake
up what do you even tell your children
when they say
[Music]
Dy get the point take a step forward I
have struggled to
find a title
for the sermon of
today really struggled because I'm using
one
narrative reported differently by
Matthew Mark and
Joan and there are several lessons to
learn and each lesson is a sumon on its
own but I want to combine all of them in
one sumon so the lesson you pick craft a
title out of
it and I pray that the Lord blesses us
the story is of
Peter every one of us when they start
that story they say when Peter was
sinking that is the
story that I want to
use Christ has just
fed 5,000
men beside women and what
children
of course people have tried to preach on
those statistics and they say women are
normally many than men and you can't
even count children where there's a
father and a mother you can be sure
there is double
triple those two
people so if we say there were 5,000 men
people have always doubled the women and
tripled or more than tripled the
children
so he didn't just feed 5,000 the Bible
records the 5,000 were men
besides women and children so I want to
believe there were over 10,000 people
that he
fed over the
years the number of men has been
dwindling in the house of God over the
years
over the
years the church is almost becoming
women
only and
children and is a cause for
alarm I was in this
University they had a l Sabbath L
Sabbath I don't know what that means
leave those that are leaving he can
student 23 23
unless
engineering
but3
24 almost exit Ambassador when he starts
to speak with authority as the
firster you love it and I called all of
them I asked them what happens between
now and the time you marry Because by
the time you get married you're no
longer in where in church you've left us
your wives and your children I think
I'll turn that into a subject in the
afternoon we look at that why do we have
few men in the house of God than the
women why are we losing the priests of
the home
why that is not the message for today I
was
saying the
miracle of that day was that only five
loaves of bread was used and to what and
to
what yeah that is what I was waiting for
and do
what yeah I can he some people say
fishes some people say fish
it doesn't
matter there were how many fish there
were how many
fishes and the loaves of bread were
five how it multiplied we can never
explain we can never describe and that
is why it is called a miracle and it fed
5,000 men beside women and
children
that
Miracle might not move you
today but if you study Spirit of
Prophecy the extent to which it moved
the
multitude they sat that day they did
want to go home because they couldn't
just
believe some guy came here preached to
us we were hungry there was no food we
only got some Adventurer that had
carried his lunch two fish five loaves
of bread he picked them prayed
multiplied collected left over how many
baskets don't be tempted to think that
the leftovers was what had been eaten
and thrown down the leftover was like if
you cook rice and you eat what remains
that people didn't do what eat is what
we call what and Mama white explains
that the leftovers were carried by
people into the villages and
cities to go and share with those that
dink 12
baskets before they left they refused to
leave the scene they said the longer
waited deliverer has done what SC and
they began to whisper why don't we just
get hold of this moment and crown him
what Ellen White explains it nicely I
love the way she puts
it she
says
all day the conviction has
strengthened that crowning Act of
feeding the 5,000 is
assurance that the longlook for
deliverer is among
them the hopes of the people rise higher
and higher this is he who will make
Judea an Earthly Paradise a land flowing
with milk and honey he can satisfy every
desire he can break the power of the
hated Romans he can deliver Judah and
Jerusalem he can heal the soldiers who
are wounded in battle he can supply all
armies with food yeah if if Christ was
the president of Kenya we we didn't we
didn't need to to have plans for
agriculture no no no no no no no no no
at there's no food in in the arried
areas there's no food there at we come
now appeal to Kenyans at one packet for
those that are dying in marsabit no
Christ just went there with with one
chapati one like this one chapati and a
bowel of beans and he will feed
everybody for all the time he'll be
there so they're looking at that kind of
a
king and they're saying our soldiers
would go to battle and if anyone died in
the battlefield they would be risen from
where
imagine imagine that kind of country
that kind of a
country he can conquer the Nations and
give Israel the long sought Dominion so
they begin to discuss and they have
plans to crown him as king and the
disciples get wind of it and remember
many of the disciples were following him
for a seat just in case they took over
what power there's a mother to some two
disciples that say please when you come
into power on your right left side put
my one M of my son on the right one put
I think the disciples operated like the
Adventist Church don't you think so yeah
when you open a hospital please remember
my son as the the cashier you know and
the son has has not even started KC
leave alone CPA has not even done
KC
so when you open that guest house please
remember my daughter remember my daugh
to be the manager of a guest house and
she has studied
education and
competing with safari park there are
someone who studied
hospitality and our institutions have
done suffered in the hands of many
Physicians that have
expertise so the
disciples quickly rally around and they
say ah these guys are thinking the way
we are thinking let us join them and
crown him asking Christ read their
hearts and quickly knew if he does not
dispers them there will soon be an
Insurrection and if there's an
Insurrection it it will hinder the work
of the gospel and he has not begun his
work so
well so he first of all decides to push
the disciples into the boat they didn't
want to go so that he can come back and
disperse the multitude no one wanted to
go he was a very humble
man from outside you would judge him and
think he has nothing to offer but when
he spoke he spoke with such an authority
that was
irresistible when he said
leave the urge to still stand was there
but you just found yourself leaving and
they left for his disciples the Bible
says he made them get into the boat and
that is why I want us to start the story
Matthew I will do the story from all the
three records until we finish Matthew
Chapter 14 verse 22 the Bible says
immediately Jesus made his disciples get
into the boat and go before him to the
other side while he sent the multitudes
away and then 23 says and when he had
sent the multitudes
away he went up on the mountain by
himself to do what to pray
now when evening came he was alone there
it means what time did you go to the
mountain probably midday I don't know
but before what
evening and when he had sent the
multitudes away he went up on the
mountain by himself to pray now when
evening came he was alone there but the
boat was now in the mid middle of the
sea tossed by the waves for the wind was
contrary I want you to notice
something today I'm preaching
extemporaneously I don't have
notes the danger in extemporaneous
preaching is that you can go
overboard even up to three is the danger
so pray we don't go beyond not keep you
within some boundaries and you want to
finish and
leave I want you to notice
something
Christ has a full knowledge of
everything he could read the hearts of
the multitude and the intention to Crown
Him King so it was not impossible for
him to know that there was going to be a
tempest in the sea is it impossible he
knew
it he knew there was going to be a
tempest in the
sea when you study verse
22 verse
22 in the Greek
bible the English Bible says it loely
that he made them get into the
boat so it's like he was pleading with
them please
go the word in Greek is not a plea but a
command he
compelled he forced them to go into the
boat it was a command
go and he
knew that in the sea they were going to
me a
tempest Move With Me
Slowly none of
us both those who are married and those
that are not
married none of
us expect a storm when we'll get into
marriage we all went with good
intentions none of
us and what drove us there was
love you found someone you could
trust and you looked into his eyes you
looked into her eyes and you felt we can
do life
together you never planned for any
mishap
in fact it's today you look back and say
how come I didn't see this thing
coming no one lives in expectation of
mishaps in marriage and family but I
want to let you
know even though
I have no
idea the pain and hurt and misery you're
going through even though I may not know
Christ knew it long
before you even say I
do it's a surprise to you but it's not a
surprise to
him that which you're going through
today
he saw it long before it ever happened
and I've always believed if he's able to
see it long before then he has a
solution in his what
hands and at times you say if the lord
loves
us why does it permit permit us to to
walk into such territory stories why
can't he just tell us early this route
you're taking is a dangerous
one and we have blamed God for the tough
situations we are going
through if he knew why couldn't he let
me know I can tell you that same Christ
knew there was going to be a tempest and
remember it's fishermen it's fishermen
with expertise that have found
themselves in a boat amidst a tempest
and he forced them into the
sea nothing takes God by
surprise he knows it
it's new to you it shocks you but he saw
it and allowed it because he knows you
can bear
it he
knows it is the Bible that says he only
permits that which you're able to do
what to
Bear it doesn't allow anything beyond
your power to
handle so I want you to sit proper and
know it is tough you have cried there is
no hope you feeling pressed on every
side but I want you to know that which
you feel pressure for you able to handle
praise the Lord you are able to
handle don't be tempted to walk
away
and then the story has
it
that he leaves them to walk into a
tempest as he goes to do what as he goes
to do what to
pray I love it as we walk into to a
tempest our savior is praying for us
when Ellen White describes his prayer he
was praying for his disciples and the
multitude to understand the nature of
his ministry and his calling so he was
praying for
them as you walk into the Tempest the
Lord is praying for
what
but the boat was now in the middle of
the
sea TOS by the
waves for the
wind was
contrary that moment must come for each
one of
us when you find yourself in the middle
of the sea and the waves arising
the wind is blowing the storms are
reaching that moment must always
come and particularly for marriage and
family it must come you like it or
not
as a matter of fact you vowed it you
even vowed
it let's leave alone those who married
the other way I'm talking about those
that had white white
weddings you
vow
think
[Music]
sing you know
it's it's
pointless they are so built and they
just carry you up like this the next
thing you know you are in a what you are
in a
house or Sim and there's a guy waiting
there and our mothers were married like
that and you were born from relations
that they didn't plan is the boy that
saw you and loved you didn't come and
ask you can I date you didn't come and
and ask you can can we get engaged you
know didn't come with a ring surprise
ring Safar P will you marry me and it's
all over
Facebook you know that that was never
there that was those
ages today we have come with st
efforts
together
MO a
b come we stay a
beach I still have it here someone sent
it to
me let
me
he's
called d d is derogative when you want
to address a woman
you look for the most derogative word
for a woman when you call
someone
and
um for once I
felt so we all got into marriage in
different ways
H in
fact even some of our pastors and Elders
it's just the other day you solemnized
your marriages is it after 20 years 30
40ch
years
okay
I love
your they will they will sort me out for
the whole
week
great
SLE
it's late just a few
hours
I'll drop you in the in the but I didn't
car
anything
[Music]
and then you be you be you get
comfortable you get
comfortable I need to be smart this time
around I will be what
smart
exra by the way we don't need to worry I
carried an
extra
no one expects what we see in marriages
today but I'm repeating the Lord knew it
the Lord saw it and he permitted
it and now you found your boat in the
middle of the sea it's being TOS here
and there you look on the East the waves
are
rising and you're
panicking it's
capsizing the person who just fed you on
the other side you wanted to Crown King
he's not even with you he went up the
what no you all alone in the middle of a
storm TOS
sea that moment must come
here but we don't
quit now in the Fourth Watch of the
night Jesus went to them walking on the
sea Fourth Watch the night was divided
into four watches from six to 9:00 p.m.
900 p.m. to midnight Midnight 3:00 a.m.
3:00 a.m. 6:00 a.m. so they were in the
fourth
watch I want you to understand something
they were moving towards capern
now and it was by a short distance by C
from beta to the point where they expect
to meet Jesus and in an ordinary weather
the journey required a few hours but now
they had driven farther and farther from
the point they
should they were
seeking it was a journey on an ordinary
weather you only needed a few
hours these guys I want to believe they
began in the first watch because other
writers say when they saw night was
falling they got into the boat they were
still standing they didn't want to leave
because they were asking themselves we
have lost an opportunity to Crown this
guy we should just have continued to
plead with him he would have accepted
and then finally they jumped into the
boat so I believe it was in the first
watch that they got into the boat second
watch on a journey so short ought to
have taken a few hours was they kept
moving farther and further from the
point that they were
seeking and it's now the Fourth Watch
they have not docked on the other side
friends there are times you thought this
which you're going through will only
take a shorter time but as time goes by
the situation grows from bad to
worse it's taking longer than you
expected and you hope to do there but
the storms keep pushing you the opposite
direction
w
and you keep
praying and
everyting announce today was a fasting
Sabbath you didn't know I fasted I have
prayed I've gone for
cash
it's taking longer than you thought
because you knew when we pray to Christ
he shows up instantly that is the notion
most of us have when we talk to Christ
he comes
immediately did you know
that his friend Lazarus
died I like how a friend of mine was
putting it in some devotion we were
having he was saying when the sisters
came to
him they didn't say Lazarus is sick they
told him
Lazarus you are
friend just to remind him if he forgot
that
because the the home of Lazarus and his
sisters is where Christ spent that is
where he bed that is where he was cooked
for that is where he showered that is
where his clothes were washed
Lazarus
seeus and he delayed until his friend
where he's given food every
day d
there are times Christ
delays because when he comes at the
moment no one will notice his
glory no one will notice his strength no
one will notice his power everyone will
think after all it was an easy thing and
at times it delays it rots goes down the
drain so that by the time he comes into
the picture you will not confuse that
power for the power of man it is
definitely the power of who
God his glory is magnified when the
situation
wasen when white discusses the story of
Peter the same same Peter we about to
discuss in prison she says that uh there
are situations the Lord allows to
deteriorate so that when he interposes
his intervention is more marked and
complete you might not understand more
marked mean everyone will do what see
it they took long in the SE
unnecessarily
longer
I know you thought it
was a two months Journey looking back is
now 14 years for
you you can't see the beauty and joy of
marriage is headed to 20 years it's
getting
worse
25 let me remind you the Lord does not
stereotype his wife workings in our
lives if he shows up for Elizabeth after
17 years it's not necessarily true he
will show up for you after 17 years
yours might be 2 years yours might be
five yours might it might even be 50
years
later the beauty of it is this when you
see he has visited Elizabeth don't cry
and say Lord why is it I pray for people
and and they give testimonies of what
you have answered and I have prayed for
them and mine is taking too long why is
it you visited so and so and you've not
visited me and at times some jealousy
creeps into you when your friend is
celebrating and you're not
celebrating when the Lord visits you not
you when the Lord visits your neighbor
you don't need to be jealous just
understand he is in your
neighborhood are we together understand
he's still within your what your
neighborhood the next door he is
knocking might be what your
door he's still in your
neighborhood you don't tell him how long
it takes I pray we learn to
rejoice in our struggles because
ultimately he must visit he
must and then the Bible says according
to Mark let me jump to
Mark Matthew has not recorded that bit
but Mark records it Mark
6 Mark chapter 6 verse
48 47 says now when evening came the
boat was in the middle of the sea and he
was alone on the land then he saw them
straining
at rowing for the wind was against them
let me repeat it then he saw them
straining he is on the land there in the
middle of the sea he saw them trining at
rowing for the wind was against them you
are at Sea Christ is at land I can
assure you his eyes are seeing you right
from where he is
right from where he is he can see how
you're
straining at throwing your
boat from where he
is there are people that have quit
Christianity because of hard times and
they have concluded God does not exist
and they have jumped into
atheism they have not jumped into
atheism because they believe that God
does not exist they have jumped into
atheism because in their worst of
moments God didn't show up at the time
they expected
him I can assure
you the Lord's eyes are watching you as
you strain are throwing your body what
he's seeing
you for the eyes of the Lord land run to
and what and
fr they can see where each of his
children are
located never be tempted to doubt his
presence never be tempted to even doubt
whether he's heard your prayer
he told Moses I have seen I know I have
heard I have now come to deliver the
Lord is seeing you at your
struggle you're not
alone he works like an
ego
when
when an eagle is teaching the baby
eagles to
fly from The Nest up there they don't
even know how to fly he's teaching them
to fly he shakes the n
so that they can fall and as they learn
to
fly when it sees one that is coming down
almost touching the ground cannot unable
to it goes and goes beneath beneath that
chinc carries
it takes it back to the
nest coming down it must come down
and he's watching as it comes down and
he realizes okay that one has not now to
fly that that one is that one is still
okay then he notice there's one almost
touching the ground just screaming
making a lot of
[Music]
noise with all this noise you're making
I can assure
you the Lord sees you you will never
touch the
ground never says when you walk in the
rivers and the waters it will not
overflow you Waters will rise slowly get
to your knees to your thighs to your
belly to your chest to your neck it will
never get to your head it can come only
up to here but never get up to here cuz
he said it will never overflow
you it can't so make all the noise you
can it's normal to
shout and I know the noise will end when
you realize the water can't go past you
your chin you will stop making noise say
by the
way
I
pray we will find
peace in our
situations
knowing the master is
watching you can never never drown
never
songwriter and I think we sing that song
understand it we just sing because the
chister say was sing when peace like a
river attendeth my what my
soul when Sor like sea belows
roll whatever my Lord thou Hast taught
me to say
It Is Well with My Soul whatever it is
that
comes the SE
toy I don't care what comes all I know
my God has taught me to say it is well
with
what I want to take a short
break we are just halfway the seron just
a short break we pray together
I want us to sing this song prayerfully
let me have let me have Dorene and uh
and this gu and
uh let me have these three leaders
prayerfully in that song As We
rise when peace like a
rer at five 30 SDA him
attendeth my the puts it
[Music]
nicely As we sing that song
prayerfully and when we are done with
that song I will request
uh brother Gordon to take us through a
prayer
session we are at Sea I don't know how
yours is mine is Tommy but I've learned
to smile the waves are raging Rising
high but I've learned to be at peace and
I pray you find the same peace today
it's tough you've considered a
separation you're considering a divorce
you're now considering even separating
bedrooms some have already separated
bedrooms one of you is sleeping with the
children you confuse the
children if it must get to a point you
don't want to sleep with your spouse
sleep in the kitchen not in the
children's
bedroom and wake up early enough before
they wake
[Music]
up what do you even tell your children
they say
[Music]
Daddy
I pray when it gets to that point when
it gets to that point you will find
peace in your heart you will say it is
well with my word because the savior is
watching let us sing that
song Let Us
[Music]
rise
when like
[Music]
a
attend my way
when
Sorrows like s be
us
wor my
Lord
thou to
sing it
[Music]
is
is with My Soul
[Applause]
[Music]
his with my
soul my
soul it is
well
[Applause]
his
my
[Music]
soul my SS all the joy of this
Glory
has my S not part but
the
is to the
cross and
I
no praise the
Lord praise the
Lord my
soul my
soul my soul
it
is it
[Music]
is
with my
soul
and the day when
my shall
be the CL be
all
and the TR shall
re and the Lord
[Applause]
shall
is my
[Applause]
soul
with
my with my
soul
[Applause]
is my
soul
[Music]
my
only one
good
[Music]
hallelujah amen thank you Pastor for the
message when you sing that song I find
myself
reflected in that song in Stan one when
peace like a
river attended my
way when sorrow like see Bow's
role whatever my Lord thou has taught me
to say it Is Well with My Soul may I
learn to say it Is Well with My Lord in
the storm stanza 2 says that my sin all
the joy of the Glorious thought my sin
not in part
but the whole but the whole is nailed on
the
cross all the waves all the Tempest
raging against us they had be nailed on
the cross with the Savior Jesus Christ
and The Last Sunset says that and Lord
Hast the day when my faith shall be
sight the Cloud be rolled back as a
scroll Jehovah Jesus Christ has the
power to roll back the scroll that has
been in your life roll back the scroll
that the devil has written in your life
in Jesus name may I find a child of God
seeking the face of Christ that Christ
you want come down come down today roll
back the this craw roll back this craw
amen because my heart is in you and my
faith is in you that you nailed
everything on the cross may God be with
you says take time to talk to our
Heavenly
Father King of
Kings Jehovah Lord you are a powerful
God surely you are Our
Redeemer you you are a miracle
worker you are a God Like No
Other King of Kings there is power in
your name and surely you are a true God
you have the power to come right in the
middle of the
storm to give us hope that my
son my
daughter I am here have come to visit
you youve paid a visit in our lives
Jehovah and your presence
makes things to roll back the scroll is
being rolled back in the name of Jesus
Christ there's a woman a lady in this
congregation crying
Jehovah but thank you for the message
that it Is
Well with My Soul
when I have the scroll rolled back by
the mighty Jesus Christ
yov may you speak to that lady may you
speak to that woman in a special way
that Jehovah however much the storm is
reaching there is hope in the sun of God
Jesus Christ that was nailed on the
cross and the storms can seize and sees
instantly in the name of Jesus Christ
there's a man in this house there is a
man in this place Jehovah crying
hopelessly so
desperate but today
Jehovah It Is Well with soul with My
Soul It Is Well with his soul thank you
for the timely message Jehovah may it
find root in ourself so that we can
magnify your name and exalt your name
forever and forever may you roll back
all the storms that has been raging in
the lives of your Saints in the mighty
name of Jesus Christ there are people
who have been fighting so many things
can be a storm of sickness can be a
storm of desperation can be a storm
Jehovah of stubborn children in the name
of Jesus Christ son of of Nazareth we
call upon your presence in these
families we call upon your visit pay
visit in these children Jehovah we are
sure of your Victory you have told us
when your encourage us when war broke in
heaven Revelation
Michael on the right hand with his
angels the dragon on the left side with
also his angels when war broke up they
were not able to Prevail against the
lamp of God and they were defeated in
the name of Jesus Christ there were no
space for the enemy to occupy in heaven
Jehovah he was cast down he was cast
down Theiss of Brethren was cast down in
the name of Jesus Christ today we are
casting you down in our families today
we are casting you down in our husbands
today we are casting you down in our
lives today we are casting you down away
from our families and our wives in the
name of Jesus Christ son of
Nazareth Jehovah cast the enemy Down Let
Your Children leave this place so
encouraged that it is well with their
soul because the savior is on the crown
Jehovah may your will be done speak to
us more as we continue let your power
and your Holy Spirit continue descending
in this place in the name of Jesus
Christ that the enemy will not find any
space to stand let him be cast down
forever and ever may you give us the
Everlasting victory in the name of Jesus
Christ we are convinced you are VCT
Victory is
sure it doesn't matter how long it has
taken Christ you are right in the place
with us let you roll back the scraw in
the lives of your children when they
come out of this place they say surely
Jehovah you have spoken remember Pastor
Elizabeth M for the wonderful and the
powerful message Jehovah that surely
there is hope in Christ Jesus however
much the storm is Raging however much
the wind is blowing however much how
montane they can be however deep they
might look king of King you can fill
them up and they become plain all the
mountains can be brought down and they
become flat in the name of Jesus Christ
that's the message you gave Isaiah 40:4
and 5
now Jehovah Lord may your Holy Spirit
continue walking with us taking us
through showing us the way with a lot of
Faith with a lot of Victory from Victory
to Victory from righteousness to
righteousness in the mighty name of
Jesus Christ son of Nazareth we pray and
believe
amen it
is let us it It Is
Well with My
Soul with my
soul
is it
is
with My
Soul
[Music]
my
amen thank you we we will call you for
one more song when we are done we are
halfway there
someon um verse
26 and when the disciples saw him
walking on the sea they were troubled
saying it is a
ghost and they cried out for
fear but immediately Jesus spoke to them
saying be of good
cheer it is I do not be afraid and Peter
answered him and said Lord if it is you
command me to come to you on the
word I want to speak
to those that are not
married on the possibility of being PR
presumptuous with
God Ellen White divides sin into three
categories there's the scene of the
appetite there's the scene of
presumption and there's the scene of
compromise of course the the sin of
appetite has got to do with our
inability to be temperate about things
it could be food it could be
whatever being presumptuous with with
God is when you get into trouble for
imagining that is what God wanted you to
do but that is not what he wanted you to
do you imagine the failure to seek the
will of God and do it so you imagine
this is what the Lord wants you become
presumptuous with God the sin of
compromise is knowing this is wrong but
you still go ahead and do
it so Peter is saying I'm not going to
walk on water if it is you I will come
at your door command command me to
come and many times I've seen people
walk into marriages with partners that
are perfect
mismatch men and women that were never
meant for you many marriages today are
not working because what you have is a m
much is someone you chose for yourself
God didn't choose for
you the Bible says a good wife comes
from where comes from the Lord and all
of you must find it in your hearts to
give God an opportunity to choose for
you a spouse and never never be
presumptuous with that choice with
God many have walked into marriages and
they're saying even oah married a harot
the Lord permitted him what you're not
understanding is that the Lord permitted
it he did it because the Lord said
it so you who's walking out of the
church has the Lord said you go
out I'm not saying we cannot marry out
of the church is a great possibility you
can marry out of the church but is that
what God is saying to you or you're
being presumptuous with
God and today you convinced them and you
wedded them in this church they are no
longer here
see say pastor but we agreed he was even
baptized she was even baptized but now
she no longer comes to
church you are pres with
God so Peter says I know I can walk if
it is you command me to come if you
command me I will
come so he said
come and when Peter had come down out of
the boat he walked on the water to go to
Jesus the character of Peter is an
interesting one many people
say is what in
English what is in
English of course you're not coming from
Uganda you know
Swahili
Peter was in the boat with the
disciples Christ is on the
water with
his I think I admire him because he he
realizes it is safer in the storm with
Christ than in the boat without
Christ it is safer
to be in the storm with Christ than in
the
boat without
Christ and when he saw that the wind was
boisterous he was
afraid and beginning to
sink he cried out saying Lord Save Me
Mama white says as in selfs
satisfaction he looked back to
see his fellow disciples just to check
just to check I don't know whether that
was that was being
um what is kiburi uh that was Pride I'm
not so sure but but white doesn't say
Pride white said as in self satisfaction
you know you can't just believe you're
you're doing what even even you today
you can to just try even in a basin you
will not so when when when you can put
your your feet in in in the water like
this and you realize you actually you're
actually walking I mean there are people
you I want to believe he was looking
just to tell
them and then white says he lost view of
Christ
and the waves came between him and
Christ and he could not see it and when
he lost view of Christ he became afraid
why because he also knew it was only
possible to walk on the water when Your
Eyes Are
Fixed On Christ and when he lost that
Focus the Bible says something
interesting that I want me to I want to
preach right now he says
this that where are we but when he saw
that the wind was boisterous he was
afraid and
begin to do
what Peter didn't
sink he
began to
sink and many a times in life you need
an experience in Sinking to appreciate
the power of
God
did you get what I
said he lost sight of Christ and
beginning to
sink and then he quickly
remembered that my problem is not the
waves the problem lies in my focus on
who Christ and quickly changed his Focus
to Christ and cried out Lord save
me you will
never testify of
God as a
Healer until you test
disase
never is
Theory had
knowledge
Jehovah you've never been sick you you
only had him as Jehovah RAF you don't
know him as Jehovah
RAF it's until you begin to lack you
will never testify of him as the
provider
never
theory is until we
lose our loved ones into the hands of
the devil you will never understand the
Lord as the deliver
never and so all of us require a sinking
experience not for the experience to
destroy us but to let us encounter God
face to
face you need
it you need
it you need that
experience
I know you're sinking but you will not
I'm pleading with you shift your focus
from the winds and the waves and the
storm refocus on Christ Jesus praise the
Lord it only requires you to shift your
focus quickly from the
storm look into the eyes of
Christ fix your eyes on Christ the
author and finisher of our what of our
faith someone has sung a song says
this how does that song
Go
Jesus look full in his
wonderful
face and the
S of us will grow strange
leading in the light of his
glory
and put your finger on that song it will
be the song we will use as we
finish Your Eyes Upon Jesus look full in
his wonderful face and the things of
Earth will grow strangely what
deep these are the men on women that go
through a storm and they can still smile
they go through a storm and their face
is still oily it
glows they go through a storm and they
still look
neat anoint yourself with what oil the
whole world doesn't need to know that
you're in a stor
no eat well dress well sleep
well and why are you sleeping well not
because you're forcing yourself to sleep
it's because the master of the storm is
right beside
you the boat will never cup size
never it's right
beside so when we preach like this you
don't imagine us we don't have we have
the biggest of problems than you but at
times we listen to you and we
say but we still leave and move we eat
well we dress well we shower every day
please don't smell don't don't don't
skip a day
because
for
now
CH come
spray yourself go to work and the Devils
at
you times you do these things to confuse
the devil look good look nice talk t
because
Christ is right beside
you and immediately Jesus stretched out
his hand and caught him and say to you
all you of little faith why did you
doubt and then when they got into the
boat the wind did what
CED I want to tell you
something Mark 6:51 when he's winding up
that story in Mark
651 Mark says
this then he went up into the
boat and the wind ceased and they were
greatly amazed in themselves beyond
measure and Marvel let me tell you
something your situation could be taking
too long the Lord is not controlled by
time and space he exists outside of time
and space but you can be so sure that
when he comes into your boat immediately
the wind will do what
cease
immediately normally we think when it
takes too long there is a struggle
between God and Satan God is never in a
competition with the devil there's no
way that the devil can compete with God
that when God pushes this button the
devil pushes this button when God pushes
this button the devil pushes this button
they're now competing to see who will
win Victory is forever with the Lord
what the Lord does is allow the devil to
exhaust his strategies his WS exhaust
every weapon he
has he doesn't need two years to show up
in your situation the long time your
problem mistaking the devil is still
exhausting his weapons don't confuse it
that God is taking too long God has
permitted him to exhaust his weapons on
you and when he's done with everything
all he needs is to step into your boat
and the wind does what
sees it's not like he's fixing a car
trying to find out where there's a
problem so it's taking too long to
diagnose and know where could be the
problem no no no no he only needs to
show
up and things
change but when John finishes it and
that's why how I want us to
finish when John finishes the story he
finishes it on a higher note than all
the other writers John chapter 6
finishes it on a higher note verse 21
listen to how John ends it 621 it says
then they
willingly received him into the boat
willingly by the way no one forces you
to receive Christ into your
situation this is another son of mine
he's single just just not
that
so so when you keep saying all of
you we are still forcing his brother to
marry so
Christ will never impose yourself
himself in your situation are you
getting me he will never impose himself
in your
situation but he will come if you
willingly receive
him what
happened then they
willingly received him into the M
listen and immediately
listen John does not talk about the wind
season
no they were in the middle of the
sea and when Christ came John says when
they willingly received him into the
boat and immediate immediately the boat
what was at the land where they were
going they were where in the middle of
the sea that is where Christ found
them John doesn't talk about the
experience with Peter but let's assume
the experience with Peter was there so
it is Christ and
Peter they still in the middle of the
sea John says when they willingly
received Christ into the boat I to him
and they found themselves on the
land you have not understood what I'm
saying they didn't need to travel a
distance to the land they didn't need to
roll the boat to the land they just
accepted him and the boat found itself
on the it was like magic twinkle of an
eye we shall be changed when Christ
comes I cannot explain it
that's why I said Christ does not need a
millisecond to work on your issues the
minute will show up your boat will be at
land it will be at
land and that is the
miracle with that
story so let it take all the years it
can take
I can assure you he's seeing
you and when he will
come you will be at the land without you
having to explain how you got to the
land because even me right now I can't
explain you will not be able to explain
how you got to the land because it is a
miracle just like you can't explain how
two fish and Five Loaves fed over 5,000
people you will not be able to explain
how you all of a sudden moved from the
middle of the sea when he just stepped
inside the boat was at the
land that's why we call him a miracle
work he still works those
Miracles and we never understand how he
does them
never never permit him work a miracle in
your
life allow him into your
boat some of us have dragged the name of
Christ in the mud people have refused to
believe him because God was using us as
an experiment for the world to know that
we serve a living God he only needed to
use you to dramatize life
but you failed
him he wanted the world to see that we
can go through a storm but we can find
our ways out of the
stor we
failed to prove to the world that he is
leaving there was some
time when I was going through my own
issues of life
and the sister-in-law asked
me
Pastor where do you get the strength to
still remain in marriage like
this all these things you're going
through you're still holding on to my
brother how do you even manage
life and I told
her
the day the
day you
here on
citizen
NTV
KBC
K24
Nation the day you hear breaking news
the god of the universe is dead ask me
question ask me that
question the day you hear the god of the
universe breaking news all over the
world the god the universe has died ask
me how I
survive for as long he still Seated on
the throne I don't survive I
leave I'm job says for I know my
redeemer it's my
prayer you will accept that which you're
going
through with
joy
and and permit God and no opportunity to
work a miracle in your life the truth is
you will just begin to sing but you will
never seek keep your eyes focused on
Christ the storms are raging the winds
are blowing the waves are rising do not
be tempted to concentrate on all that is
happening
Focus fix your eyes on Christ you will
walk on the
Storm when he gets into your boat you
shall be at
Sea may the Lord Jesus bless us in his
mighty
name what was that song is it in the
Hypno yes
I am asking that we come and and sing
there was another singer she was
called asking that we sing that song 290
and then when we are done with that song
we want to offer special
prayer we want to offer special prayer
and the song will sing after this song A
Sweet
Hour of Prayer
290 is the song Turn Your Eyes Upon
Jesus when we are done with that song we
do which is that other one
478 so let us all rise we are singing
two
songs after we are done with the first
song you have 3 minutes
to speak to the master of the
storm about your case 3
minutes and when we are done we will
sing Sweet Hour of Prayer and I will ask
Molly to finalize it with
prayer 29
[Music]
Soul are you we and
TR no light in the darkness you
see there's night
for
[Music]
theor
life more
abund and
Free
Turn Your Eyes Upon
[Music]
[Applause]
Jes and the
things of Earth will grow
Str in the
light of his
glory and
prise through
death
life
stand we
fall
all more than
con we
are Your
Eyes Upon
[Music]
Jesus his
wonderful
and
all God will grow
strange in the
light of his
glory and
gra is what shall not fa
you
and all will
be then go to
our
is his
perfect
Sal
[Music]
[Applause]
to Your
Eyes Upon
[Music]
Jesus his
wonderful and the
God will grow
strange
de in the
light of his
glory
and his word shall not fail you he
promised it leave him and all will be
well you have 3
minutes to tell
Jesus the storm you're in believe
it believe
him and you will not
fail you have
time when you're done with the prayer 3
minutes find some space when you're done
with your personal prayer standing
find some
space to kneel when you're done with
yours
standing you will find some space to
kneel no when you're done with you are
standing we will sing Sweet Hour of
Prayer and then we will nail for final
prayer okay
yeah
see
and everlasting God Amen king of kings
and Lord of lords amen the Creator who
was never created the mighty one of
Jacob the Holy One of Israel The
Sovereign of the Seas that no wave can
surpass your voice father we come before
thy throne of grace this sabbath day
with Thanksgiving in our hearts that
this far you have been ezar thank you
for the gift of life thank you for the
gift of Salvation thank you Jehovah for
the gift of this sabbath day thank you
for the power of your word my father
that you have spoken that though the
waves May roll though the Tempest May
rage though the sea the storms may be
tossed but at the end of the day we have
on our side The Sovereign of the Seas
amen that no wave my father no wave can
surpass your voice be it waves of
diseases be it waves of Affliction be it
waves of joblessness be it waves of
barrenness be it waves of wayward
children be it waves of rebellious
children be it waves of adultery in
marriages be it waves of demonic
possession and oppression father no wave
can surpass you your voice amen
therefore Lord we come before the throne
of grace this afternoon that we may
plead for Mercy for each and every
personing need amen father we are
sinners not even worthy to stand before
your present we have sinned in our words
we have sinned in our thoughts and we
have sinned in our actions and many
times when we try to do good it is sin
that we encounter father we come
clinging to the old ragged cross this
afternoon that Lord have mercy according
to your steadfast love forgive us our
transgressions my father blot out our
iniquities oh Lord cleanse us wash Us by
the blood of Jesus cleanse us from all
man of sin cleanse us from all forms of
unrighteousness cleanse us from all
forms of ungodliness Father sanctify us
once more my father that when we bring
our petitions before you may we come
holy may we come pure may we come clean
and acceptable that our petitions may
come before you as sweet Aroma in the
name of Jesus Christ
amen father thank you for this family
week of prayer that you have used your
manservant pastor Elizabeth to minister
unto your children father it has been a
word in season for our families thank
you for the word that you have put in
her that Lord at such a time we need
families that can stand to be counted
amen we need families that can bear the
burden of the Cross and infirmity of
others that the church May stand amen
father the family is the first church
the family is a sanctuary that is why
the devil is not giving peace to
families Jehovah are families that are
the brink of breaking there are families
Jehovah that are trusting in you for the
fruits of the womb there are families
that are threatened by sexual immorality
there are families that are threatened
by poverty and joblessness there are
families that are threatened by
rebellious children there are families
that have children struggling with
demonic possession yet they still don't
know about
it father it is a sad situation
but I thank you Lord that when we look
at the cross we live amen that there is
power when we look at the cross amen
that is why Lord the song writer says we
should turn Our Eyes Upon Jesus because
just like Peter when we lose Focus On
Christ we begin to sink amen and I thank
you Lord that sometimes you allow us to
go through situations that we may be
reminded that it is not by our
it is not by our might that we are alive
today but it is Christ who lives in Us
by faith amen therefore Lord this
afternoon we plead with you my father
forgive us for all the times we have
doubted Your Love forgive us for all the
times we have doubted your power forgive
us for all the times we have doubted
your ability to save forgive us for all
the times the material things of this
world that you have given us have made
us to forget to f focus on you the
provider the Healer The Giver forgive us
Lord and help us strengthen us once more
give us the power to pray that we may
focus on the cross once again amen
father this
afternoon I want to thank you for the
testimony of our sister yesterday that
Lord once more you proved that you are a
God who answers prayers amen and I know
even today there's someone in this
congregation
who is bearing a burden that maybe they
know or they don't even know about it
may be a sister somewhere it may be a
family somewhere my father trusting you
for the fruit of the womb yes it may be
someone somewhere who is even D he the
real priest of his family because of
joblessness and he cannot provide for
his wife and children there is a family
somewhere my father that love has left
that oh and all they know is nagging and
misunderstanding and constant chaos
father there's a family somewhere this
day that is experiencing hopelessness
because of frustrations and deceptions
of the devil that has put in their
family today Lord we lift these Souls
unto you there's also a young man
somewhere Jehovah who is trusting in you
for a marriage partner there's a girl
who's been in this church who is even
wondering Lord if you even know her but
Lord I want to encourage her today that
she is inscribed in the palm of your
hand that Lord you may you may seem to
TI but your time is always the best and
everything every plan for us is for our
welfare and our future and not for
Destruction father visit each and every
hous old this afternoon in Jesus name
each and every head represented here
father meet each and every person at
their point of need in Jesus mighty name
father you are The Giver of children you
say children are a Heritage you say
children are a blessing father those
families with rebellious children
intervene in their situations come the
storm in those families my father speak
peace be still into the lives of those
children that their parents may
experience the blessing of having
children in the name of Jesus Jesus
father those trusting in you who are
jobless my father father how can they
return tithes and offerings when they
have nothing in their pockets and in
their bags Lord come down restore their
financial prosperity in Jesus name every
good gift come from you my father bestow
upon them the blessing of finances that
they may return their tithes that they
may give offerings that they may also
contribute
to the advancement of the Gospel
Ministry in Jesus mighty name father we
come as a Congregation of donam SDA
church this afternoon that Lord have
mercy on us once more according to your
steadfast love amen father how can we
experience City Jehovah let us not be in
church but we experiencing inadequacy
and scarcity in our lives and even our
families father in The Book of Psalms 34
you said that the Young Lion may suffer
hunger the Young Lion may experience
lack but those who fear the lord we lack
no good thing therefore my father what
is lack doing in our families what is
anger doing in our families what is
divorce and separation what is
frustrations anguish Agony sorrow pain
and struggle doing in our families
father if it is for the glory of your
name then give us peace PE that we may
wait upon you so that we may experience
your glory in Jesus name and if it is
the work of the devil the devil has no
power the devil has no authority over us
because he who is in US is greater than
he who is in the world Amen therefore
Lord we rebuke every evil altar that may
be speaking against families this
afternoon in Jesus name amen every evil
Parts in families that in families girls
cannot get married in families boys
cannot marry in families people cannot
have children every evil pattern and
plan of the enemy father we plead for
the power of the blood of Jesus that let
the blood of Jesus erase those patterns
in Jesus mighty day every ancestral Cur
every generational curse that is
speaking against your children this
afternoon Lord we ple that just the same
way you called Abraham out call our
families out from every generational and
ancestral cast in Jesus name let the
blood of Jesus delink let the blood of
Jesus disconnect that the blood of Jesus
may be the only altar planted and
speaking for our families in the name of
Jesus father patterns are
frustrating if you're in a family
Jehovah all girls are unmarried time you
find in families Jehovah all girls have
children in their father's houses
everyone in a family is experiencing
joblessness alcoholism in families
Jehovah Insanity at mental illness
father we know those are narratives of
the devil to frustrate your children and
we come against them in Jesus mighty
name generational curses of drug abuse
Jehovah we refuse we reject them in the
name of Jesus that our children will
live to testify of the goodness of the
Lord in the land of the living in Jesus
mighty name Spirit of alcoholism we
reject them we denounce them we cast
them out on authority of your word in
the name of Jesus that father you gave
us power to trample over serpents and
scorpions this afternoon Jehovah every
wave of evil that is frustrating and
suppressing our families we trample upon
them in the name of Jesus and we LIF the
reason savior up that Christ you are the
master of the stone amen speak peace
into our sisters speak peace into our
siblings speak peace into our children
speak peace into our homes that every
storm every CH let there be peace be
still in Jesus mighty name
amen
of the tri of Judah Arise My Father
arise take up your shield and backler
and fight for every family in this
congregation today in Jesus mighty name
that Lord let us experience your power
let us experience your grace let us
experience your might that when we go to
heaven when you come to take us home May
our children not be left behind in Jesus
name when you come to take us home May
our spouses not be left behind in Jesus
our siblings be amongst the food
soldiers when you lead us captain of the
mighty Throne may we be among the army
of the Lord who will say truly this is
our Lord whom we have been waiting for
amen Lord we bless your name we thank
you we lift your name on high that Lord
you give peace that this world cannot
understand and I thank you Lord that
even in our situations my father you
have never ashamed us you have always
given us peace that's why we glow we
glow because we know we serve a lord who
is captain of the mighty Throne The
Sovereign of the Seas that when he leads
no matter how the storms are
raging all is well
and it is well with our souls therefore
Lord this afternoon I bring every family
into captivity to your obedience that
Lord intervene in our situations in
Jesus name amen our children some are at
home right now because of school fees
father provide school fees in Jesus
mighty name father some don't even know
where the next meal is going to come
from father open doors of abundance open
doors of Heaven Jehovah pour your
abundance upon our families in Jesus
name amen some of us are struggling with
secret sins some of us are struggling
with diseases my father we are just
walking out here but we always claim
that this is our sickness it is not our
sickness in Jesus name amen no disease
belong to anyone father your intention
is that we may we may experience
prosperity of Health therefore Lord
every disease let them go back to where
they originate from in Jesus name that
everyone who comes to the pool of
Bethesda which is Don home SDA church
this afternoon may they experience a
miraculous healing of their physical
ailments in Jesus mighty name father we
thank you we lift your name on high for
you are a mighty Redeemer and those who
wait upon you are never disappointed you
renew their strength like that of an
eagle those who put their trust in you
my father you never let them die down
therefore Lord our hope is in you you
are our strength you are our provider
you are our keeper you are our sustainer
thank you for the leadership of this
church thank you that they allowed this
week of prayer to be here it is not in
vain my father I know a family somewhere
a soul somewhere has been touched
through the ministry of Pastor Elizabeth
this week and Lord it is that your name
may be glorified it is not Pastor
Elizabeth it is not the the the Family
Life leaders it is not even the pastor
of this church it is the exalted risen
Christ therefore Christ ex manifest your
power manifest your power let the Holy
Spirit move in a mighty way in this
congregation this afternoon in Jesus
mighty name amen we thank you we honor
you may all glory be unto you this My
Prayer by faith in Jesus mighty name
amen
get the point take a step forward